Vashisht Hitansh

 $vhitansh@gmail.com \mid https://www.linkedin.com/in/vashisht-hitansh-0a9906140/ \mid \textbf{312-443-2629} \mid https://www.linkedin.com/in/vashisht-hitansh-0a9906140/ \mid \textbf{312-443-2629} \mid https://www.linkedin.com/in/vashisht-hitansh-0a9906140/ \mid https://www.linkedin.com/in/vashisht-hitansh-hitans$

SUMMARY	
☐ Software Quality Assurance with more than 7.5 plus years of experience in ETL/Data warehouse	testing.
☐ Automation Tester with more than 5 years of experience in and automating manual test cases.	
☐ AWS Certified Associate - Solutions Architect and Developer.	
☐ Experience with Automation testing using SQL, Python and Cucumber/Gherkin Framework.	
☐ Experience with backend data quality testing using SQL on TOAD/Oracle.	
☐ Experience in Big Data testing involving Hadoop, Hive and Amazon Redshift.	
☐ Experience in Smoke, Functional, Integration, System, Regression, Backend and Performance Te	sting
☐ Experienced with both Waterfall and Agile project development methodologies	
☐ Experienced with Web Services, XML and Restful services testing.	
☐ Experienced with Functional, Regression and System testing using Manual and Automated testing selenium WebDriver.	g tools -
WORK EXPERIENCE	
Senior Quality Engineer, MathWorks – Natick, MA (Sept 2018 – Present)	
☐ Tested the ETL Data Flows regularly which extracts data from various sources (Files, tables), transite the data through Business Objects and loads in the data warehouse plus the target data mart.	nsforms
☐ Developed extensive SQL (Source minus Target) Scripts to compare data and test the data integrit compliance with the business rules.	ity in a
☐ Developed Automated Quality Checks on the high priority data marts using Stored Procedures and creating data flows and workflows.	ıd
☐ Developed Quality metrics dashboard on Power BI to report test coverage for various departmusing Python scripts to connect to SonarQube API and parsing the JSON data and inserting the SQL tables.	
☐ Lead UAT testing sessions with business users and the development team, represented users by accounting for user data, and source system to DW environment integration needs	
☐ Heavily involved in report testing on power BI and BO universe.	
Senior Testing Specialist, Capital One - Chicago, IL (May 2015 – Aug 2018)	
\Box Lead a team of offshore and onsite QA resources for building test automation tools and delivering quality data.	g high
☐ Developed an Automation Testing Framework using Cucumber, Gherkin, Python and SQL Script replacing an existing manual testing approach.	ting for
☐ Tested the data flow in an ETL application on AWS EMR which extracts data from Apache Kafk transforms data through a Spark job and loads the transformed files to AWS S3/Amazon Redshift	
☐ Developed extensive SQL (Source minus Target) Scripts to compare data and test the data integrit compliance with the business rules.	ity in a
☐ Applied CI/CD methodology to set up the application for an automated deployment to production environment.	1

☐ Designed Cloud Formation Templates to create EMR, EC2 instances, S3 buckets, SNS and automated it through Jenkins.
☐ Developed Python API for logging standard/transactional data elements as an JSON object into a file, AWS S3, AWS SNS, and KAFKA.
☐ Successfully executed Load/Performance tests to stabilize AWS EMR infrastructure by producing very high data rates through Kafka.
Automation Tester, Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan - Detroit, MI (March 2014 – April 2015)
☐ Developed extensive SQL scripts by analyzing Source to Target Mapping documents using TOAD to communicate with the Oracle Backend for data accuracy, integrity and security checks.
☐ Involved in requirement gathering of the Data Warehouse, ETL testing effort, analyzing business requirements, Data Model Design, Data flow from various Sources to Target.
☐ Involved in Web Services Testing using SoapUI tool. Validated request and response XML.
ETL/BI tester, KAR Auction Services (ADESA) - Carmel, IN (August 2012 − November 2013) □ Validated the data files from source to make sure correct data has been captured to be loaded to target □ Prepared Test Cases based on ETL Specification Document and Use Cases.
☐ Tested Web Services, Validated Request and Response XML, Restful Calls using SoapUI. ☐ Selected the Test Cases to be automated and performed functional testing of the front end using Selenium (IDE and Web Driver).
TECHNICAL SKILLS
☐ Scripting Languages: SQL, Shell Script, Python
☐ Amazon Web Services : EC2, EMR, CloudFormation ,S3, SNS , Redshift
☐ Relational Databases – Oracle, Teradata, MYSQL
☐ Tools: Jenkins, JIRA, COGNOS, Business Objects, Tableau, Power BI, HP Quality Center
☐ Hadoop: Hive, Hue, Kafka
CERTIFICATIONS
☐ AWS Solutions Architect (Associate)
☐ AWS Developer (Associate)
EDUCATION

F

University of North Carolina Charlotte - Master of Science, Computer Science, May 2012 Pune University, India - Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology, June 2009